Mmm it's-a Orange Juice
Hey guys, this is yarn from Orange Juice
Today I'll be talking about a basic game mechanic, pushing units
You can push slower units with faster units
Here the hog pushes the giant skeleton
And as a result he pushes to the tower faster, which allows him to get an extra hit in
To understand how this mechanic works, lets break it down
A Hog is a "very fast" moving unit
A Giant Skeleton is a "medium" speed unit
A Mini P.E.K.K.A is a "fast" moving unit
The "very fast" hog and the "medium" speed giant skeleton averaged out to be "fast"
It's a compromise, but it makes sense to execute this with certain combos
The Dragon shoves the Balloon to the tower about one second faster
It's not going to get an extra attack in
But that one second is devastating with a Balloon
If you're too eager with your timing and plant the Balloon too close, it'll stumble with the Dragon
Alternatively, you can push "very fast" units with other "very fast" units
The Hog has a one second deploy time
During this deploy time, you can shove the Hog with melee Goblins
It's not going to win you the game but every little detail adds up
You must have good technique or this will back fire on you
Planting the Hog too late will cause the goblin to run in front of the Hog
One second doesn't seem like much, but that's one second less for your opponent to react
Here's a concrete example demonstrating just how useful this technique truly is
The archer locked onto the tower one second earlier
Whereas if she didn't get pushed, she would've targeted the barbarians
She ended up doing over 300 damage to the tower
Not bad, considering most people would've just let her die
If you have any video requests, make sure to comment below
Thanks for watching, don't forget to like and subscribe for more quality OJ